Guide to the David Westheimer literary papers, 1940-1997 MS 345
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series I: Works, 1942-1997
  - The Olmec Head - Printer's Copy (3 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Olmec Head - Galleys (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Olmec Head - 2nd draft screenplay (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - The Olmec Head - Correspondence, reviews, publicity (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Our Sister - Concept, story line, rough draft, miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Our Sister - 1st draft, revised 1st drafts (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Our Sister - 2nd draft (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Out on a Limb" (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Over the Edge - 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Over the Edge - Research (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Over the Edge - 1st draft (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Over the Edge - drafts (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Over the Edge - printer's copy (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Over the Edge - Correspondence, 1967-1981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Over the Edge - Publicity, Miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - "The Pet Canary" (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - The Phantom Hero (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - "Poor Old Charlie Johnson" (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - "Portrait of a Young Lady" (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Pro and Con - notes (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - The Pro and Con - 1st drafts (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Pro and Con - story treatments, 2nd draft (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Radio Scripts: "Anybody's Child"; "The Man Who Liked Dickens"; "Overdose"; "A Way With Children" (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - "A Rainy Afternoon" (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - "The Rescue" (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - "The Revolution" Script (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Rider on the Wind - Concept for Novel (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Rider on the Wind - Research Materials (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Rider on the Wind - 1st draft (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Rider on the Wind - 2nd draft (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Rider on the Wind - Revised Draft (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Rider on the Wind - Revised Draft (1977); folder 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Rider on the Wind - Revised Draft (1977); folder 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Rider on the Wind - Proofs (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Rider on the Wind - Correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Rider on the Wind - Correspondence, 1982-1985, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "The Salesman Looked Like Tony Curtis" (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - "The Screaming of Iggles" (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Short stories, notes (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Short stories, article (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Short stories, T.V. plots (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Short stories - related correspondence, 1949-58 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Sitting it Out - original manuscript; folder 1 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Sitting it Out - original manuscript; folder 2 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Sitting it Out - original manuscript; folder 3 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Sitting it Out - 2nd draft; folder 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Sitting it Out - 2nd draft; folder 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Sitting it Out - 2nd draft; folder 1 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Sitting it Out - 2nd draft; folder 2 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Sitting it Out - 2nd draft; folder 3 of 3 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Sitting it Out - Early Draft; folder 1 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Sitting it Out - Early Draft; folder 2 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Sitting it Out - Early Draft; folder 3 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Sitting it Out - Draft; folder 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Sitting it Out - Draft; folder 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Sitting it Out - Draft Copy; folder 1 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Sitting it Out - Draft Copy; folder 2 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Sitting it Out - Draft Copy; folder 3 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Sitting it Out - Kathleen Lindsay edited version; folder 1 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Sitting it Out - Kathleen Lindsay edited version; folder 2 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Sitting it Out - Kathleen Lindsay edited version; folder 3 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Sitting it Out - Rice University Press Revision; folder 1 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Sitting it Out - Rice University Press Revision; folder 2 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Sitting it Out - Rice University Press Revision; folder 3 of 3 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Sitting it Out - Author's Corrected Proof; folder 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Sitting it Out - Author's Corrected Proof; folder 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Sitting it Out - Revised Duplicate Set; folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Sitting it Out - Revised Duplicate Set; folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Sitting it Out - Revised Duplicate Set; folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Sitting it Out - Revised Duplicate Set; folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Sitting it Out - Revised Master Set; folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Sitting it Out - Revised Master Set; folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Sitting it Out - Proofs (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Sitting it Out - Printer's Copy; folder 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Sitting it Out - Printer's Copy; folder 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Sitting it Out - Prints (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Sitting it Out - Disks (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence, Notes (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence A-G (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence K-M (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence N-W (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence: Harold Ober Associates (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence: Rice University Press (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Sitting it Out - Correspondence: Rice University Press 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Sitting it Out - Rejections (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Sitting it Out - Houston Trip 1992 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - "Six Yards of Damascus" (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - "Small, But Comfortable" (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Song of the Young Sentry - 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Song of the Young Sentry - Notes (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - Early draft (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - Early draft; folder 1 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - Early draft; folder 2 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - Early draft; folder 3 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - 3rd draft; folder 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - 3rd draft; folder 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - 4th draft; folder 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Outer Compound/Song of the Young Sentry - 4th draft; folder 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Song of the Young Sentry - printer's copy; folder 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Song of the Young Sentry - printer's copy; folder 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Song of the Young Sentry - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Story ideas and clippings (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Such as Amy Fox" (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Summer on the Water - 1947-1949 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Summer on the Water - "Come Sit With Us, Honey" (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Summer on the Water - "Come Sit With Us, Honey" - short story from which Summer on the Water is derived (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Summer on the Water - original ms (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Summer on the Water - galley proof (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Summer on the Water - reviews (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Summer on the Water - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Term Paper - English 100 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Think About Paris" (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - This Time Next Year (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - This Time Next Year - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Trouble Comes to Town - 1973 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Trouble Comes to Town (A Stranger in Town) - 1st draft (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Trouble Comes to Town (A Stranger in Town) - 2nd draft (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Trouble Comes to Town (A Stranger in Town) - 3rd draft (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Trouble Comes to Town - draft treatments (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - T.V. Scripts, ideas (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - T.V. Stories - Correspondence (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Two the Hard Way (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - "Until One of Us is Dead" (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - A Very Private Island - 1st draft (Heart's Desire) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - A Very Private Island - Printer's Copy (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - A Very Private Island - Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Von Ryan's Express - 1963-1965 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Von Ryan's Express - outline before 1st draft (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Von Ryan's Express - section of "false start" draft (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Von Ryan's Express - 1st draft, chapter I-XIV (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Von Ryan's Express - 1st draft, chapter XV-end (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Von Ryan's Express - 2nd draft, chapter I-XIV (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Von Ryan's Express - 2nd draft, chapter XV-end (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Galley Proof (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Printer's Copy (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Von Ryan's Express - film treatment (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Von Ryan's Express - screenplay (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Revised screenplay, July 31, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Royalty Statements [ON INDEFINITE LOAN] (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Correspondence; folder 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Correspondence; folder 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Von Ryan's Express - Correspondence, Miscellaneous material (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Von Ryan's Express - miscellaneous material (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Research (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Research on Italy (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Research on Switzerland (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Von Ryan's Return - 1st draft (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Von Ryan's Return - 1st draft, revised (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Von Ryan's Return - 2nd draft, revised (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Proofs (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Reviews, Publicity (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Correspondence; folder 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Von Ryan's Return - Correspondence; folder 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Watching Out for Dulie - 1960-1962 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Watching Out for Dulie - 1st draft (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Watching Out for Dulie - 2nd draft (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Watching Out for Dulie - Galley Proofs (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Watching Out for Dulie - Duplicate Reviews; jacket (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Watching Out for Dulie - Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - "A Way with Children" (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - "Whose Little Boy Are You?" (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Wrong Prescription (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - "You Can Walk on Their Backs" (Box 26, Folder 15)
- Series II: Houston Post Columns and Correspondence, 1984-1988
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - June 1984-Aug. 1984 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Sept. 1984-Oct. 1984 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Nov. 1984-Dec. 1984 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Jan. 1985-Feb. 1985 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - March 1985-April 1985 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - May 1985-June 1985 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - July 1985-Aug. 1985 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - July 1985-Aug. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Nov. 1985-Dec. 1985 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Jan. 1986-Feb. 1986 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - March 1986-April 1986 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - May 1986-June 1986 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - July 1986-Aug. 1986 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Sept. 1986-Oct. 1986 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Nov. 1986-Dec. 1986 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Jan. 1987-Feb. 1987 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - March 1987-April 1987 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - May 1987-June 1987 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - July 1987-Aug. 1987 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Sept. 1987-Oct. 1987 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Nov. 1987-Dec. 1987 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Jan. 1988-Feb. 1988 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - March 1988-April 1988 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - May 1988-June 1988 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - July 1988-Aug. 1988 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Houston Post Columns (originals) - Sept. 1988-Nov. 1988 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Houston Post Guest Columns - 12-12-1988 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - Jan.-July, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - Aug.-Dec. 1986 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - Jan.-July 1987 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - Aug.-Dec. 1987 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - Jan.-June 1988 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - July-Dec. 1988 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - 1989 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - non-dated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Houston Post Readers - May 1983, 1984-1986, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 7)
- Series III: Correspondence by name of correspondent, 1942-1994
  - Correspondence from George Baroni, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Lynette Burgess, 1985; 1993 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Joseph Consolmagno, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from Ralph Cushman, 1991, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from General Benjamin Davis, 1992, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from William Eckhardt, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Joseph Frelinghuysen, 1988-1990; 1993 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence from Ruth Freund, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from Campbell Geeslin, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Betty Harman and Nancy Meador, 1988-1990 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with James Thomas Jackson, 1966-1973 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with James Thomas Jackson, 1974-1983 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with James Thomas Jackson, 1983-1985 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - James Thomas Jackson: "Buffalo Bayou: Oh, What a Time it Was" (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - James Thomas Jackson: "Hopeth All Things" Part I and II (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - James Thomas Jackson: "A Lesson in Compassion from My Father" (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - James Thomas Jackson: "Shades of Darkness" outline; Chapter 3, Book 2; Chapter 4, Book 2 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - James Thomas Jackson: "Terry and Me" (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - James Thomas Jackson: Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from Charles Jennette, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence from Peter Joseph, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence from Dana Kennedy, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with Lawrence C. Kennedy (Pilot of B-24 crew and fellow POW, deceased) (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence from Joe Kilgore, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence from George Kinsura, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence from Kitty Lindsey, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with Claude McLeod, 1987-1989 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence from Daniel Miller, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence from David Nagel, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence from Michi Nakamura, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence with Dorothy Olding (Literary Agent), 1985-1989 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence from Walter Rhein, 1943-1945; 1993 (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence with Rice University, 1964-1989 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence with Rice University, 1990-1994 (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Abraham Rothberg: 1956-1969 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Abraham Rothberg: 1970-1975 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Abraham Rothberg: 1976-1982 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Abraham Rothberg: 1983-1987 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Abraham Rothberg: 1988-1990 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Abraham Rothberg: 1993 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Abraham Rothberg: articles and works (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Jerry Segal, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with William J. Slattery, 1981-1989 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Bill Smallwood, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with J.D. Thomas, 1987-1990 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Betty Tucker, 1987-1989 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Frances Vick, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Major General Louis Walsh, 1983-1987 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence from Wandrey Books, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Arnold A. Wright: "Behind the Wire" (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Kazuhiko Yusa (convicted murderer in Osaka Prison) (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Family Correspondence, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with Families of POWs, WWII, 1942-43 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Families of POWs, WWII, 1944-1945 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - "Dear Mom" POW Letters by David Westheimer, 1942-1945 (Box 30, Folder 21)
- Series IV: Chronological Correspondence, 1945-1996
  - Correspondence: 1945-1947 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: 1954-1955 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: 1956-1957 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: 1964 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: 1965 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: 1966 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: 1967 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: 1968 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1969 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1970 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1971 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1972 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1973 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1974 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1975 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1976 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1977 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1978 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1980 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: 1982 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: 1984 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-May 1985 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: June-Dec. 1985 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: 1986 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Jan.-June 1988 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: July-Dec. 1988 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1989 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1990 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: A-B (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: C-E (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: F-G (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: H-K (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: M (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: N-P (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: R-S (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: T-W (1990-1991) (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: A-C (1991-1992) (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: D-L (1991-1992) (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: M-R (1991-1992) (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: S-W (1991-1992) (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: General, 1992-1993 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: A-G (1993-1994) (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: H-P (1990-1994) (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: R (1992-1994) (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: A-W (1996) (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: A-W (1985, 1992, 1994-1996) (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: C-W (1994-1996) (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Carolco (1992-1994) (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: General, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: n.d. and miscellaneous (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous Material, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 33, Folder 16)
- Series V: Biographical Materials, 1940-1970s
  - Photos of David and Dodie Westheimer, 1940, 1968, and n.d. (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Newsclippings re: David Westheimer, 1960s-1970s (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - WWII Group Photos (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Personal Notebook (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Travel Expenses and Documents - 1965 (Box 33, Folder 21)
- Series VI: Oversize Materials
  - Photos of David Westheimer (Box 27)
  - Houston Post Columns and Reviews, 1939-1949 (Box 27)
  - Newspaper Scrapbook, 1950-1960 (Box 27)
  - Lighter Than a Feather Wall Maps (Box 27)
- Series VII: Addendum
  - Sub-Series I: Works, Houston Post Colums
    - Avila Gold - Screenplay (Revised First Draft) (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Avila Gold - Dailies (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - The Big Bang - Draft (pt. 1) (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - The Big Bang - Draft (pt. 2) (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Delay En Route - 1st Draft (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Delay En Route - Edited 1st Draft and Book Jacket (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Going Public 2000 - Novel (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Going Public - Screenplay (Originally "Kill Fee") (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Going Public - Screenplay (Originally "Kill Fee") (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - The Great Wounded Bird- Proof, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Assorted Poetry Associated with The Great Wounded Bird (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Josie - Unedited Draft Copy (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Lighter Than a Feather - Japanese Edition (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - The Magic Fallacy - Popular Library Edition (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - The Magic Fallacy - Screenplay (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - The Magic Fallacy - Alley Theater Version (Copy) (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - The Magic Fallacy - 1st Draft (Copy) (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - The Magic Fallacy - 2nd Draft (Copy) (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - The Olmec Head - Screenplay (Originally "Chato") Uncorrected (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - The Olmec Head - Screenplay (Originally "Chato") (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Princess Midnight - Screenplay, 11/26/1992 (Revised 1st Draft) (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Princess Midnight - Screenplay by David Westheimer (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Princess Midnight - Original Screenplay by Carlos Blair (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Snake Music - 1st Draft (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Snake Music - Revised 1st Draft (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Snake Music - Dailies (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Houston Post Columns - Notebook of Topics and Ideas for Articles (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Houston Post Columns- Clippings (photocopies), 07/02/1984-12/31/1984 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Houston Post Columns- Clippings (photocopies), 01/07/1985-12/09/1985 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Houston Post Columns- Clippings (photocopies), 01/04/1986-12/09/1986 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Houston Post Columns- Clippings (photocopies), 01/03/1987-12/28/1987 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Houston Post Columns- Clippings (photocopies), 01/02/1988-12/20/1988 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Senior Women Web - Articles by David Westheimer, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 18)